asx.com.au 2019-09-15

# Privacy Statement - ASX

## Contents

  * Introduction
  * What personal information does ASX collect? 
  * How does ASX collect personal information?
  * How does ASX use and disclose personal information?
  * Legal basis for processing personal information
  * How does ASX use personal information collected through cookies?
  * Does ASX transfer personal information overseas?
  * Sensitive information and government identifiers
  * Data security
  * Data retention
  * Your rights
  * Marketing activities and opting-out
  * Consent to use of personal information
  * Avoiding phishing and scams
  * Links to other sites
  * Contact us
  * Updates to this Privacy Statement

### Introduction

This Privacy Statement explains how your personal information is collected and used by ASX, and your rights in relation to that information.

References to “ASX”, “ASX Group”, “us”, or “we” are to ASX Limited and its related bodies corporate. References to “you” or “your” are to individuals whose personal information is collected by ASX. “Personal information” includes any information about an identified or identifiable individual.

### What personal information does ASX collect? 

The personal information that ASX collects includes:

  * name, date of birth and personal contact details including email, phone number and address;
  * business contact details including email, phone number, address, company and job title;
  * billing and payment details;
  * marketing preferences, interest in products or services or contractual relationships with ASX;
  * IP address, computer name or login details for ASX systems or portals;
  * survey responses, feedback or complaints;
  * website usage information; 
  * records of access to our premises, including CCTV footage;
  * voice recordings; 
  * financial holdings information, shareholder status, and other information collected under the ASX Operating Rules; and
  * any other information required for the purposes of collection described below.

ASX collects personal information about the following persons (or their staff):

  * shareholders;
  * suppliers;
  * employees;
  * listed entities, participants and issuers;
  * customers;
  * candidates for employment;
  * potential new listed entities, participants or customers;
  * third parties seeking services or seeking to provide services;
  * subscribers to ASX information;
  * subscribers to the ASX sharemarket game, education and webinars; and
  * other individuals who we come into contact with in the ordinary course of business.

### How does ASX collect personal information?

ASX collects personal information in a variety of ways, including through:

  * direct contact with individuals, including in business activities, at events and through correspondence by mail, telephone, and email;
  * subscriptions to ASX notifications or marketing communications;
  * our website, including registration forms on our website for courses, games, education or services;
  * recruitment processes;
  * the use of cookies on the ASX website;
  * publicly available sources;
  * in some circumstances, from third parties, including when you provide personal information to a third party for the purpose of sharing it with us, such as a recruitment agency.

When we collect and process personal information, we will inform you about such collection and processing, and will seek your specific consent when required by applicable data protection laws.

### How does ASX use and disclose personal information?

ASX will not process or disclose your personal information other than for the purpose for which we have collected it unless required by law to do so.

ASX uses personal information:

  * to provide education services;
  * to service shareholders;
  * to service ASX customers, subscribers and individuals participating in ASX events and games;
  * to provide ongoing information about our products and services to you where you have expressed an interest in such information;
  * to provide you with relevant products and services;
  * to administer its relationships with employees and contractors;
  * to enable the resolution of a concern or complaint;
  * for security purposes such as monitoring and detection to protect ASX’s systems, infrastructure, information and other property;
  * to comply with industry standards and regulatory and legal requirements;
  * to fulfil its functions and obligations as a market licensee, clearing and settlement (CS) facility licensee, benchmark administrator licensee, Australian Financial Services licensee or other licensed or regulated business;
  * to consider potential services and service providers.  
In certain situations, while it is not our preference, failure to provide your personal information to ASX may prevent ASX from being able to effectively provide a service, product or response to you, for example where we are required to collect personal information by law or under the terms of a contract.

Where required, ASX will disclose personal information to:

  * entities within the ASX Group;
  * our technology partners who support our systems and services;
  * person(s) to which the information is required to be disclosed by a legal or regulatory obligation, such as under a subpoena or court order.

We may disclose personal information to other third parties under contracts we enter into with them for the provision of services, where permitted under applicable laws. Where we do so, our contracts will require those parties to keep that information confidential and secure and to treat it in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. 

### Legal basis for processing personal information

ASX uses or discloses personal information in the following circumstances:

  * to enable ASX to comply with its legal and regulatory obligations, such as statutory obligations imposed on members of the ASX Group under the Corporations Act, including as a listed entity, market operator, CS facility operator, benchmark administrator, Australian Financial Services licensee or other licensed or regulated business;
  * to enable ASX to discharge its licence obligations as a market licensee, CS facility licensee, benchmark administrator licensee, Australian Financial Services licensee or other licensed or regulated business;
  * to enable ASX to discharge its obligations under the ASX Operating Rules, which have effect as a contract under seal between ASX and its participants, as well as monitoring and enforcing compliance with those rules in accordance with its obligations under the Corporations Act;
  * to enable ASX to discharge its contractual obligations, including under employment contracts or when providing products and services to, or receiving products or services from, third parties;
  * where you have provided us with your consent to the use or disclosure, or a third party (such as the organisation you represent) has obtained your consent to the use or disclosure;
  * to fulfil a legitimate interest of ASX, where that interest is not overridden by your interests, rights or freedoms.

### How does ASX use personal information collected through cookies?

Our website uses the following types of cookies:

  * Necessary cookies: These cookies are required to allow our website to function properly. They help make our website usable by enabling basic functions such as page navigation.
  * Statistics cookies: These cookies help us to understand how website visitors interact with our website by collecting and reporting information anonymously. This allows us to improve the effectiveness of our website.
  * Marketing cookies: These cookies are used to track visitors across websites to allow us to tailor marketing information on our website and with our advertising partners.

ASX collects personal information through cookies for its legitimate interests:

  * to authenticate access to certain areas of the website, such as the MyASX section, the customer portal and ASXOnline;
  * to monitor traffic levels and flows;
  * where permitted under data protection laws, to provide better products and services and tailor our marketing information; and
  * from time to time, to conduct surveys.

If you use our website, ASX will collect your personal information through cookies for the above purposes. If you wish to restrict or block certain cookies such as third party cookies, you can generally do this through your web browser settings (the “Help” function within your web browser should tell you how) or via the following link: https://youradchoices.com/. If you do not allow cookies, some features and functionality of our website may not function or operate as expected.

Information obtained through use of cookies is recorded into ASX’s server log which is provided by your browser. Where possible, ASX will anonymise data to protect an individual’s anonymity. However, there will be circumstances where ASX will not be able to provide a service unless your limited personal information is provided. We will try not to identify you except: in the event of an investigation, where a law enforcement agency exercises a warrant to inspect the service provider’s logs; if your usage is causing technical issues for ASX’s website which need to be resolved; or where you may have won in a game. In these circumstances, we may need to identify you to contact you. ASX partners with Dianomi for ad serving. For more information on ad serving and information on ‘Opting-out’ please visit https://www.dianomi.com/legal/privacy.epl.

### Does ASX transfer personal information overseas?

ASX does not generally transfer personal information to overseas parties unless required by law or enforcement activity or unless working with international service providers. ASX shares or stores personal information with vendors who have been contracted to provide customer relationship systems and technological solutions. These parties are subject to confidentiality obligations, and they are also subject to applicable data protection laws. When ASX transfers personal information overseas to third party service providers, it will ensure that appropriate safeguards are in place as required under applicable data protection laws, such as standard contractual provisions or ensuring that the third party has an appropriate certification. Personal information is encrypted where possible when transferred overseas and ASX and its third-party service providers make every effort to protect your personal information.

These third-party service providers change from time to time and may be located in Australia, the United States, Japan, the United Kingdom and other countries. You can contact ASX at the details below for a list of the current countries.

### Sensitive information and government identifiers

ASX does not collect sensitive information about an individual unless the individual has consented or it is required by law to do so. Sensitive information includes personal information such as an individual’s criminal record; health information; membership of a professional or trade association; or membership of a trade union.

Government identifiers such as Tax File Numbers will generally not be collected or used unless required by law or the ASX Operating Rules, or where necessary to complete a transaction or service.

### Data security

ASX takes reasonable steps to protect personal information it holds from misuse, interference and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. ASX has a number of security measures, processes and standards in place to protect personal information, and requires its third party partners to comply with appropriate confidentiality obligations and security requirements such as industry standards for information security.

### Data retention

Where personal information is no longer required for the purpose for which it was collected ASX will take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify the information, unless it is required to allow ASX to address any complaints or legal or compliance matters or for another purpose permitted under applicable laws, or where ASX is required by law or a regulatory obligation to retain it. ASX will take reasonable steps to destroy unsolicited personal information received from third parties that does not serve an appropriate purpose unless it is required by law or a regulatory obligation to retain it. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, ASX considers the nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the purposes for which it is processed and the applicable legal requirements. When ASX deletes personal information it will be removed from our active database, but it will generally remain in archival or back-up systems for a period of time where it is not practicable or possible to delete it. In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal information (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research, statistical or data analysis purposes, in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. If you would like further information on the retention periods we apply to your personal data, please contact us in writing at the details below.

### Your rights

Under Australian privacy law, you have the right to request access to your personal information held by ASX and to request that your personal information be corrected. Depending on the nature of your personal information and the purposes for which it is processed by ASX, you may have the right under applicable data protection laws to request the deletion of your personal information or in some circumstances, to restrict or object to the processing of your personal information. If you would like to take steps to exercise any of your rights, please contact us in writing at the details below. A fee may be charged for providing access if permitted under applicable law.

ASX takes reasonable steps to ensure that personal information held about you is accurate, complete and up to date. Please advise us in writing of any changes to your information using the contact details below.

### Marketing activities and opting-out

ASX collects personal information from the web site www.asx.com.au through receiving subscriptions or registration of courses, games and services. If you have previously provided consent, we may from time to time email you about an event or new feature, product or service that we think might be of interest. If you request not to receive such emails at any time, we will stop sending them to you. To make this request, you only need to unsubscribe or opt-out. Alternatively, you can contact us at the details below.

### Consent to use of personal information

ASX will notify you and obtain your consent at the time of collecting your personal information where required in accordance with applicable data protection laws. This notification will include the following:

•    A description of the purposes for which your personal information is being collected.  
•    That ASX may share your personal information with our approved partners who provide services on our behalf.   
•    That ASX will maintain your data until it is no longer required or you request us to delete it from our systems, unless it is permitted or required by law or regulatory obligation to retain it.  
•    That you can opt out of receiving communications from us at any time by clicking unsubscribe or contacting privacy@asx.com.au.  
•    A link to this Privacy Statement.

### Avoiding phishing and scams

If you are a broker-sponsored investor on ASX, we will hold your personal and financial information in CHESS, a CS facility operated by ASX. This information will include your HIN (Holder Identification Number), your name, address and any email address, your residency status and the financial products you hold in CHESS. When you communicate with ASX, we may ask you to confirm those details to assist us with identification. However, we will never ask you to provide other personal or financial information such as passwords, date of birth, bank account balances, portfolio balances or your personal bank account details, or instruct you to pay funds into third party bank accounts.

  If you receive a communication from someone who claims to be from ASX and who asks you to provide your personal or financial information, this may indicate that you are the target of a scam. If this happens to you, please immediately report this to ASX by calling 131 279 or by sending the details to us at info@asx.com.au.

Your prompt action can assist us to minimise the impact to other market users of ASX-related scam activity.  

You can report any non-ASX related scam activity to SCAMwatch (a scam reporting website run by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission) at http://www.scamwatch.gov.au/.

### Links to other sites

This site links to other non-ASX sites. ASX is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.

### Contact us

ASX has appointed a Chief Privacy Officer to manage privacy enquiries and complaints. They can be contacted by phone, post or email at:

Address:    
ASX Limited  
Level 6  
20 Bridge Street  
SYDNEY NSW 2000  
Telephone: 131 279  
Email: privacy@asx.com.au 

You can also obtain information or lodge a complaint at the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner’s website at www.oaic.gov.au

### Updates to this Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement will be reviewed from time to time as required. We reserve the right to update this Privacy Statement from time to time to reflect changes in the law or technology or business practices. It is your responsibility to review the updated Statement.

Last updated: August 2019
